<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>evernote on Mark Percival</title><link>http://mdp.github.io/tags/evernote.html</link><description>Recent content in evernote on Mark Percival</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mdp.github.io/tags/evernote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tumblr's shoehorned JS watches for dirty tricks</title><link>http://mdp.github.io/2013/06/09/tumblrs-js-is-watching-what-you-type.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mdp.github.io/2013/06/09/tumblrs-js-is-watching-what-you-type.html</guid><description>I stumbled across this the other day on Tumblr. One of the issues with letting people render any HTML they want on your domain is that nefarious users can render a password field on an official looking page and capture the input from the victim.
Tumblr seems to have come up strategy to try and prevent tricked users from entering their passwords.
View the source and you&amp;rsquo;ll see that they inject the following JS on the top of every page load before the &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; tag.</description></item><item><title>Evernote doesn't really care about security</title><link>http://mdp.github.io/2013/03/02/evernote-doesnt-really-care-about-security.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mdp.github.io/2013/03/02/evernote-doesnt-really-care-about-security.html</guid><description>So Evernote got hacked. Suprised? I&amp;#8217;m not.
First off, let me quickly note that I actually use Evernote on a daily basis and like the product very much. It&amp;#8217;s great for taking notes and stashing the digital cruft I inevitably accumulate; email receipts, travel confirmations, snippets of articles, all go into my Evernote account. I even hacked up a script to send my Github Gists into Evernote so I can search them more easily.</description></item><item><title>Reworked my Gist importer for Evernote</title><link>http://mdp.github.io/2013/02/24/reworked-my-gist-importer-for-evernote.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mdp.github.io/2013/02/24/reworked-my-gist-importer-for-evernote.html</guid><description>Reworked my Gist importer for EvernoteIf your looking to import your Github gists into Evernote and make them searchable, this is your starting point.
The code is quite brittle, but it does the job, as I&amp;#8217;ve been running it for around a year. Not something I&amp;#8217;m looking to spend much time on, but feel free to run with it on your own; it&amp;#8217;s MIT licensed and such.
Find out more at: https://github.</description></item></channel></rss>